你要找到叶之书
You'll need to find the Book of Leaves.
你每天都在接近
You are closer every day.
洛伦佐正在会见乌尔比诺公爵
Lorenzo makes an embassy to the Duke of Urbino.
漂亮!
Brilliant!
他希望与他们建立新的军事联盟
He seeks to create a new military alliance.
我已经很久没有带人参加过战斗了
It's too long since I led my men into combat.
看来 我们的请求非常适时
Our proposal is timely indeed.
给我干掉美第奇家族
End the House of Medici.
不然我就干掉你
Before I end you.
谁宵禁后还在街上闲逛 我就把他的名字
Those caught roaming the streets after curfew
记到册子上
get put in my little book.
无论什么理由 违反宵禁的人都会被记录下来
Anyone who breaks curfew, for the slightest reason, will be put down here.
包括那个真正的间谍 那个诬陷贝奇的人
Including the true spy whom you believe framed Becchi.
怀疑教廷计划是什么下场
You've seen what happens when people question
你见过了吧?
the plans of the Vatican, haven't you?
朱利亚诺 应该可以成为卡米拉的好丈夫...
Giuliano, he'd make a fine husband for Camilla.
钥匙
The key.
在罗马
It's waiting in Rome.
你母亲还活着
Your mother, she's alive.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: Leon
翻译：SceneryJuly 爱哈利波特 落寞卷菜 sharefans_竺
校对：sharefans_竺 影子
达芬奇的恶魔 第一季第7集
只有他自己
He's alone.
这还是几天来的第一次
For the first time in days.
你自己看看 琐罗
See for yourself, Zo.
小心
Careful.
镜片刚刚调好
The lenses are delicately balanced.
全城都在过狂欢节 他到这来做什么?
Why is he here while the rest of the city's busy with the carnival?
那墓碑上刻的什么名字?
What's the name on that headstone?
我看不清
I can't make it out.
镜片可以再调
The lenses can be adjusted.
给我
Here.
西莉亚・利西马科斯
Celia Lysimachus.
这是个犹太姓氏
That's a Jewish surname.
难怪被埋在贫民墓里
Explains why she's buried in a pauper's graveyard.
她是谁?
Who is she?
她和瑞阿里奥什么关系?
And what is she to Riario?
大概是臭味相投吧
Maybe only gets stiff for the stiff.
有可能
You might be right.
他要走了
He's on the move.
大师 我们已经跟踪瑞阿里奥好几天了
Maestro, look, we've been following Riario for days.
- 万一被他发现...  - 不会的
- If he sees us...  - He won't.
莱昂 虽然我不会被瑞阿里奥吓得尿裤子 我还是同意尼科的看法
Leo, while I'm not about to piss down my leg, I have to side with Nico.
我知道那阿比西尼亚人说那钥匙的另一半在这里 但是你看啊
I know the Abyssinian claimed the other key's here but look around.
罗马有几千年的历史
Rome's been growing for thousands of years.
要藏一样东西 没有比这里更难被人发现的地方了
An object looking for a place to hide couldn't have chosen a better home.
没错 所以我们才要把它从那个
Indeed. And that's why we're going to liberate it,
瑞阿里奥自以为安全的地方拿走
from the one place Riario would expect it to be safe.
梵蒂冈的秘室
The Vatican's Secret Archives.
记住 你生于尘土亦湮于尘土
Remember, man, that thou art dust and unto dust thou shalt return.
远离罪孽 克拉丽斯
Turn away from sin, Clarice.
忠诚于福音
And be faithful to the Gospel.
我会的 哥哥
I try, brother.
如马太教导 我愿为迫害我的人祈祷
As Matthew urges, I pray for those who persecute me.
记住 你生于尘土亦湮于尘土
Remember, man, that thou art dust and unto dust thou shalt return.
我拿到了南城门的守卫换班图
I've got the guard rotations for the south entrance.
巡查紧得像耶稣受难日的尼姑一样
Tight as a nun on Good Friday.
我们查了每座城门 窗户
We've examined every entrance, window,
地道 城墙的破洞
tunnel, hole in the bloody wall.
发现根本不可能混进去
Getting in uncaught is impossible.
"不可能"这个词只会让我更想尝试
You do realize "impossible" is just a word that makes me try even harder.
大师 每处城门都有哨兵巡逻
Maestro, sentries patrol every possible entrance.
其实 那边就来了两个
In fact, here come two now.
别担心 朋友
Don't worry, my friends.
只要他们以为你们是犹太贫民
As long as they think you're Jews here in the ghetto,
你们就不用担心
you have nothing to fear.
没人会在意犹太人
As Jews we are beneath notice.
看啊 你们穿着黄色衣服 他们都不看你
You see, they pay no attention because you wear the yellow.
感谢你带我们进来
Thank you for taking us in.
即便你们不是来为我们除掉罗马暴君的
Even if you are not out to undermine our oppressors,
我们也要欢迎琐罗的朋友
friends of Zo are always welcome
因为他没几个朋友
because he has so few.
连接梵蒂冈的圣天使堡呢?
What about the Castel Sant Angelo that connects to the Vatican?
要是我可以设法接近塔楼...
If I can devise a way to reach the tower...
莱昂 听着 你听我说
Leo, listen. Just listen to me.
那是个监狱
It's a prison.
好吗? 你那么喜欢待在巴格鲁监狱吗?
Okay? Did you enjoy your time in the Bargello that much?
你想念铁栅栏了吗?
You're homesick for iron bars?
把我关进铁栏杆的正是他们 琐罗
These are the people who put me behind those bars, Zo.
他们要为此付出代价
And they will pay for their folly.
- 再见  - 再会
- See you.  - Farewell.
尼科洛
Niccolo.
你的妻子卢克蕾齐娅信教吧?
Your wife Lucrezia, she is a believer, is she not?
是的 阁下
She is, Your Magnificence.
她身体不好吗? 我最近没看到她
Well, is she unwell? I've not seen her of late.
她去锡耶纳照看她的姑妈了
She's been caring for an aunt in Siena.
我希望她能在这里 不过或许上帝另有安排
I'd hoped she'd be here by now but perhaps God has other plans.
殿下
Your excellency,
我可以冒昧地说句 你看上去很虔诚吗?
would it be impertinent of me to say you wear your ashes well?
我喜欢冒昧的女孩
I like my women with a bit of cheek.
我要的违禁名单你都找到了?
You've gathered all the curfew ledgers as I asked?
- 找到了 先生  - 很好
- I have, signor.  - Excellent.
搬到我房间去
Bring them to my quarters.
噢 弗朗切斯科
Oh, Francesco.
节日快乐
Buone Feste.
我们把不愉快都忘记吧
Let us heal old wounds.
好的 忘记之前的不快
Yes, and put old feuds to death.
我们期望两家可以团结
We look forward to the union of our families.
我们可以把嫁妆的事谈妥
Assuming we can work out the terms of the dowry.
他在开玩笑
He jests.
我相信那不成问题
I'm sure it will sort out.
既然你首先表示友谊
Since you've extended the first laurel,
我们愿意出资为家族
we'd like to host an engagement fete for the families
主办订婚宴会
at our country estate.
也是复活节前夕的圣餐
A Lord's supper for Holy Saturday.
这太好了 弗朗切斯科
This is good news, Francesco.
对佛罗伦萨好 对我们大家都好
This is good for Florence and this is good for us all.
- 那就复活节前夜见了  - 好的
- Till Holy Saturday then.  - Indeed.
保重
Farewell.
做得好
Well done.
现在你只需把这消息告诉朱利亚诺
Now all you have to do is break the news to Giuliano.
首先说清楚 我在此时事上别无选择
Let's be clear on this, I get no choice in this matter.
是的 因为你是我弟弟
None. Because you are my brother,
这就是你别无选择的原因
you get an explanation of why you have no choice.
卡米拉・帕吉
Camilla Pazzi.
你必须承认她很迷人
You can't deny she is attractive.
如果我需要新情人 肯定会睡了她
If I needed a new mistress, I'd bed her myself.
帕吉家还有其他的未婚少女 但就没这么漂亮了
The Pazzis have other marriageable maidens without so much appeal.
克拉丽斯也是在关心你
Clarice was looking out for you.
你都不问我一下就决定了?
You decided all this and you didn't even consult me?
我们想着如果帕吉家拒绝的话
We thought that if the Pazzis turned us down,
我们就不用麻烦你了
we wouldn't have to burden you with it.
你还真是站着说话不腰疼
Easier to say from the seat of the bidder rather than the bidded upon.
你真的觉得这样能行吗?
Do you honestly believe this can work?
从我们祖先阿维拉多开始 帕吉家族就是我们的敌人了
The Pazzis have been our foes since the days of our ancestor Averardo.
如此的宿仇是不会化解的
Feuds like that don't just go away.
所以人们才发明了和亲
This is precisely why marriage was invented!
巩固势力 化解宿仇
To consolidate power and to settle feuds.
度 我一直清楚要为自己的身份付出代价
Yeah. I always knew I'd pay for being me.
卢克蕾齐娅 你在罗马做什么?
Lucrezia. What are you doing in Rome?
谁说我们在罗马的?
Who says we're in Rome?
我是怎么到这儿的?
How did I get here?
我告诉你我爱你
I told you I loved you.
所以我找到了方法
So I found a way.
而且别以为我没注意到
And don't think I didn't notice
你还没回答我的问题
you haven't answered my question.
开始比结束时更容易抵制
It is easier to resist at the beginning than it is at the end.
但话说回来 或许你根本不懂爱
But then again, perhaps you're not capable of love.
当我给你自己的珍爱时 你仍然保持沉默
You stay silent even when I've given you my dearest possession.
你还看不出来你对我的意义吗?
Can't you tell from this what you mean to me?
你就不能跟我说我想听的吗?
Can't you tell me what I need to hear?
我...
I...
没有爱 活着还有什么意思
Without love, there is no point in living.
嘿 嘿! 醒醒 醒醒
Hey, hey! Rouse yourselves. Rouse yourselves.
我找到去梵蒂冈的路了
I've discovered a way into the Vatican.
走开 你还醉着呢
Bugger off. You're still drunk.
那个没有守卫的地方 那个入口
What is the one place, the one entrance,
在哪呢?
where no guard can be found?
在水里
It's in the water.
下水道是根据维特鲁威原理建造的
The sewers were built on the principles of Vitruvius.
可以贯穿整个城市
Designed to flow freely into the city,
包括梵蒂冈
including into the Vatican.
快看 快看
Look, look.
空气进到玻璃瓶里让火焰可以燃烧
The air is delivered into the glass and it allows the flame to live.
你真是糊涂了 你钻不进那玻璃瓶的
Now I know you're besotted. You won't fit inside there.
当然不行 但我们可以造一个相同性能的装置
Of course not, but we can construct a device of similar properties.
看这些草图 这儿 在这儿 看
Look at these sketches. Here. Here. Look.
快看
Look.
这是套潜水服
It's a diving dress.
是仿照水龟的呼吸原理制作的
It's modeled on the breathing of a water turtle.
空气通过这条线进去
Because the air goes in through this line,
然后进到前面的袋子里
and then it's exhaled into this forward pouch.
听着 我们需要收集材料 动作要快
Look. We need to gather some items and do it quickly.
我们只有几天时间了
We've only got a few days.
- 给你  - 猪皮 玻璃...
- There.  - Pig's skin, glass...
渔网...
a fishing net...
- 还有船?  - 是的 船
- a boat?  - Yes, a boat.
没错
Right.
就是这个地方
This is the spot.
好了 要保证这个装置稳定地运行
Okay, just continue operating the mechanism at a steady pace
直到我到达目的地
until I reach my destination.
一旦我到了 我会塞住这头作为停止的信号
Once I'm there, I'll plug the end of this line as signal to stop.
莱昂 你确定这装置能行吗? 我们还没有试验过
Leo, are you sure of this contraption? We haven't tested it.
没有时间了 我们不能被发现 就当勇闯火线吧
There's no time if we're to remain undiscovered. It's trial by fire.
或者说水线
Or water, in this case.
只管拉风箱吧
Just keep pumping these bellows.
幸运的话 只要几个小时就可以进去了
With any luck, it'll take just a few hours to get all the way inside.
要是你把浮出的地点弄错了
What if you're wrong about where you'll emerge
碰到大队卫兵怎么办?
and you climb up into a brigade?
维特鲁威的图案显示了下水道的走向
The plans of Vitruvius show where the drains lead.
对吧? 一旦到达蓄水池
Yes? Once I reach the reservoir,
我会钻到梵蒂冈的地面上
I just drill up into the Vatican flooring.
如果我日落时没出现
If I don't reappear by sundown,
你们就单独回佛罗伦萨
make your way back to Florence without me.
- 日落?  - 不是吧? 怎么需要这么久?
- Sundown?  - Honestly? What could take so long?
嘿 该打烊了
Hey. Bell time.
打烊了
Bell.
再来一杯!
Another!
美第奇先生 今晚打烊的时间到了
Signor de Medici, we're about to ring the bell for the night.
那给我一桶酒 让我搬回家通宵畅饮
Then bring me a barrel I can roll home and drink all night.
给我再多的戒酒建议也不为过
I need all the liquid counseling I can get.
你能相信我哥哥逼我娶一个女人...
Would you believe my brother pledged me to marry a woman from...
好了 姑娘们
All right, skirts.
德拉戈奈蒂的卫队很快就会来了
Dragonetti's wolves will be here for a round-up soon.
该回家了
It's time to find your beds.
您也是
You too,
大人
your grace.
要是我想在你床上过夜呢?
And what if I called your bed my home for tonight?
抱歉
Sorry.
酒喝多了
Too much cider.
看来我的老二不知道什么是好的
Seems my cock doesn't know what's good for him.
幸好我知道
Luckily I do.
真奇怪的声音 你听到了吗?
Strange noise. Did you hear that?
琐罗 有人来了
Zo, Zo.
在这下面吗?
Is it down there?
不是 走吧
No, come on.
琐罗 快点
Zo.
我给你煮了汤醒酒
I boiled you some quinto quarto for your hangover.
很有效的
It works wonders.
你真是个圣女
You're a saint.
我想昨晚说明我不是了
I think we disproved that last night.
哦...
Oh...
有些事你必须知道
There's something you have to know.
我已经订婚了
I'm betrothed.
你说过了
You mentioned it.
好几次
A few times.
我恰恰是因为你订婚了才同意你的示爱的
I agreed to your advances precisely because you're spoken for.
如果你没订婚 我们又爱慕上了彼此
If you were unattached and we became enamored with each other,
你能想象会发生什么吗?
can you imagine what might happen?
美第奇家的人娶了平民
A Medici marries a commoner.
有这么糟吗?
Would it be so bad?
瓦妮莎小姐?
Lady Vanessa?
你的宫殿不过是华丽的监狱
Your palace is a prison with better linens.
一举一动都被监视 被人评头论足
Every move is watched, every action judged.
我在此的选择或许有限
My choices might be limited here,
但我只需忠于自己
but I answer to no-one but myself.
我何不放弃一切来和你生活在一起?
Why don't I sack it all and come and live with you on your side of things?
没有美第奇家族的治理
Without the Medici hand governing,
我会永远活在修道院的谎言里
I'd still be living a lie in the convent.
但那是善意的谎言
It would have been a gentle lie,
在朋友中的谎言...
a lie lived among friends...
哦
Oh.
但如果我娶了卡米拉・帕吉 那也是一个谎言
But if I marry Camilla Pazzi, that's a lie too.
你娶了她 你会化干戈为玉帛
When you marry her, you neutralize that family of fiends.
当统治佛罗伦萨压力太大时
And when ruling Florence gets to be too much,
你我仍然可以不时地偷欢
you and I can still snatch a little freedom here and there.
这样很好啊
You know this makes good sense.
还有事让你犹豫
Something else stops you.
我觉得是帕吉家族害死了贝奇
I blame the Pazzis for Becchi's death.
是他们陷害了他
They set him up somehow.
与罗马还有他们的间谍一起
Along with Rome and their spy.
那就洗清他的罪名
Well, then, clear his name.
之后帕吉就知道是什么样的人生活在他们中间了
And then the Pazzis will know just what sort of man lives among them.
阿门
Amen.
请允许我介绍费德里科・达・蒙泰费尔特罗
May I present Federico da Montefeltro,
乌尔比诺公爵
the Duke of Urbino.
- 费德里科  - 阁下
- Federico.  - Your Eminence.
感谢你不远万里 迅速来此
Thank you for travelling so far, so quickly.
随时候命
Anything for Your Holiness.
我只是上帝的仆人
I am but a servant of God.
而你却联合
And yet you ally yourself
你的教子洛伦佐・美第奇对抗我们
with your godson Lorenzo de Medici against us.
是吗? 真是奇闻了
Do I? A surprise to my ears.
- 嗯  - 我懂了
- Hm.  - I see.
那你是否认在家和洛伦佐会面
So you deny meeting Lorenzo in your home
商讨结盟对抗教皇统治了?
to negotiate an alliance against the Papal States?
请原谅我的侄子
Please forgive my nephew.
那些谣言让他非常生气
These rumors have angered him greatly.
不需道歉
No apologies necessary.
要是我 我也会如此气愤的
If I'd heard similar, I'd react the same.
或者更糟
Or worse.
为我们对抗美第奇家族 就赏你五千金弗罗林
5,000 gold florins to fight for us against the Medicis.
现在 你必须道歉了
Now, apologies are necessary.
你认为雇佣军只是为了钱杀人?
You think Condottieri kill only for money?
有些是为了乐趣
Some I kill for pleasure.
费德里科 在谈正事前先让你了解情况
Federico, let's have you refreshed before we discuss our business.
我们稍后再聚
We shall reconvene after.
先生?
Signor?
美第奇先生?
Signor de Medici?
谁啊?
Who's there?
美第奇先生索要了这些名单
Signor de Medici requested these lists.
德拉戈奈蒂终于给你索引了?
Dragonetti produced the index of symbols?
我得偷偷地进入他的办公室
I had to invade his office without his knowledge.
我不打扰你们工作了
I'll let you gentlemen get to work.
昨晚的杂活还没干完
Somehow I never got to my chores last night.
- 小姐  - 再见
- Signorina.  - Bye.
告诉我 天秤座代表谁?
Tell me. Who's Libra?
抱歉 殿下
I'm sorry, Eccellenza.
这是金泰尔・贝奇的标志
It's the symbol for Gentile Becchi.
天秤座 正义的天平
Libra, the scales of justice.
能让他知道这个就好了
If only we can deliver that to him.
- 摩羯座?  - 摩西医生
- Capricorn?  - Moses the physic.
可以理解 疾病可没有宵禁
Understandable. Illness respects no curfew.
那就剩下双子座了 他是谁?
That leaves Gemini. Who is he?
我不认为双子座代表了叛徒
I don't think our conspirator is Gemini.
这个符号是...
That's the symbol for, well...
卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂?
Lucrezia Donati?
冒犯之处请原谅 但您肯定知道她为何这么晚还在外面
Forgive any indelicacy, but you surely know why she's out late at night.
我确实知道
I do.
但是 我们雇佣达芬奇的那周
And yet, the week we hired Da Vincis,
- "从锡耶纳返回"  - 是的
- "Returning from Siena."  - Mm.
我听说现在她就在那儿 可能是在探望亲戚
I hear she's there now. She could have been easily visiting relatives.
也可能是去了罗马
She could have just easily traveled to Rome
警告他们我们有了新战争工程师
and alerted them of our new war engineer.
不可能 她可是... 女人啊
It's impossible. She's a... woman.
正是
Exactly.
她和我哥哥的关系成了天衣无缝的托辞
Her liaisons with my brother create an unquestionable alibi.
但我们不能排除卢克蕾齐娅是间谍的可能性
But we cannot ignore the possibility that Lucrezia is a spy.
备马去锡耶纳
Saddle the horses for Siena.
我们当面问她
We'll question her directly.
先生们 请集合
Gentlemen, gather round.
这是博纳多・巴隆切里
Bernardo Baroncelli.
这是贾科莫・ 波拉乔里尼
Jacomo Bracciolini.
佣兵队长乔瓦尼・巴蒂斯塔
Condottiere Giovan Battista.
这是雷纳托・朱斯蒂尼
Renato Giustini.
巴尼奥内神父
Father Bagnone.
马菲教父
Father Maffei.
尊敬的奥尔西尼红衣大主教
Your Eminence, Cardinal Orsini.
有人会说我们是叛国贼
Some may call us conspirators.
我认为不 绅士们
I say no. Gentlemen,
在座的每一位都是我们伟大城市的救世主
look upon each other as saviors of our great city.
啊
Ahhh.
这位就是最后一位救世主
And here's our final savior.
先生们
Gentlemen.
- 前门被锁上了  - 谁这么大胆?
- The front door was locked.  - Who dares?
莱昂纳多・达・芬奇
Leonardo Da Vinci.
那个你试图囚禁并烧死的人
The man you sought to have imprisoned and burned.
那个佛罗伦萨的大师
The Florentine virtuoso.
你进来的方式和特别
You make quite an entrance.
要确保我们不被人打扰啊
To ensure a private audience.
密室 请带路
The Secret Archive, if you please.
如你所愿
As you wish.
我知道外面有护卫
I'm aware of the guards outside.
密室
Surely a Secret Archive
当然会有一个秘密通道
has an attendant secret passageway.
那就找出来啊
Then find one.
这所教廷由尼瓦罗・斯佩齐亚里设计的 对吧?
This palace was designed by Nivolo Speziali, no?
他的建筑风格在历史上很有名
And his structures are historically rife
他喜欢运用暗门
with hidden doorways,
隧道
tunnels.
根据微风的方向
And judging by the direction of that breeze,
我认为...
I would say...
通道就在这堵墙后面
a passageway most likely lies behind this wall.
我赞同洛伦佐绝妙的联姻计划
I have agreed to Lorenzo's cunning plan of a marriage,
因为它绝对不可能实现
only because it will never happen.
美第奇家族答应要在圣周六(复活节前夕)过来
Accepting it obliges the Medicis to join us here on Holy Saturday.
要在洛伦佐过来的路上动手吗
Do we kill Lorenzo coming up the path
还是让我们的人埋伏在途中?
or have my men attack along his journey?
瑞阿里奥伯爵命令 只有他们兄弟两个在一起的时候 我们才能动手
Count Riario commands that we strike only when the brothers are together.
洛伦佐和朱利亚诺的喜好不同
Lorenzo and Giuliano enjoy separate but equal sway
但臣民不是效忠于此便是效忠于彼
over the loyalties of the people.
如果他们没同时死
If they are not killed simultaneously,
幸存者会重新掌权
then the survivor will reclaim power.
一旦把他们兄弟除去 我们就能削弱他们的势力
Eliminate both brothers at once and we cripple their line.
只要他们死了
And as soon as they're dead,
纳扎雷诺・德拉戈纳迪就以他的值夜官身份 掌权
Nazzareno Dragonetti, with his Officers of the Night, steps in.
我们能相信他吗?
Can we be so sure?
那可是一个效忠美第奇家族多年的人啊
This is the man who spent years doing the Medicis' bidding.
我也怀疑
I must agree.
那么 你又拿什么来证明你的忠诚呢?
What assurances do we have that your loyalty lies with our purpose?
我效忠于我的家庭
My allegiance is to my family.
效忠于弗洛伦萨 我的家乡
And to Florence, my home.
那洛伦佐的妻子怎么办呢?
And what of Lorenzo's wife?
我的妹妹克拉丽斯
My sister, Clarice.
如圣经所言
As the Bible says,
女人一结婚就不再是娘家的人了
a woman leaves her home when she weds.
某种意义上 她已经不是你妹妹了
She's no longer truly your sister.
但是
However,
等到最终你回到罗马 你真正归属的地方的时候
you will be handsomely rewarded for the loss you endure,
你的付出会换来丰厚的回报
as you finally return to Rome where you belong,
圣父的副司祭
Vice Chancellor to the Holy Father.
在座每一位都将获得丰厚的报酬
As each of you will be rewarded.
这不正是洛伦佐的做法吗?
Isn't this what we complain of in Lorenzo?
他已然不再是帝国的领导了
That he is not a leader of a republic
而是一个只顾及宠臣的暴君吗?
but a tyrant dividing his spoils among his cronies?
我们就不能改变这种任人唯亲的局面吗?
Are we just exchanging one family of nepotistic leaders for another?
巴斯塔!
Basta!
喝杯酒 兄弟 然后冷静点
Take a drink, brother, and calm down.
像其他新上任的领导一样...
Like any new leaders, we...
忠于我们的人能平步青云
we promote those loyal to us.
但洛伦佐是一个懦弱 贫穷
But Lorenzo is a weak, bankrupt traitor
躲在政治特权的庇护下的叛国贼
hiding behind political privilege.
如果欧洲知道是这样一个人在统治我们的帝国
How is Florence a world power
佛罗伦萨还能如何掌控世界?
if Europe knows our republic is in such hands?
帕吉家族能够利用他们的贸易伙伴
The Pazzi name offers legitimacy and security
和联盟军队提供合法保护
with trade partners and neighboring armies.
检验你忠诚的时候...
The time to question your allegiance is...
哦 已经过了很久了
well, it's long past.
美第奇兄弟将会这样死去
That is how the Medicis will die.
转瞬之间
Quickly.
效忠于我们 或者... 死
Stand with us or... not at all.
维克洛・玛娜
Viccolo della Manna.
安娜・多纳蒂 卢克蕾齐娅姑妈的家
The home of Lucrezia's aunt, Anna Donati.
女士 您是安娜・多纳蒂吗?
Signora, are you Anna Donati?
我们找你的外甥女卢克蕾齐娅
We require your niece, Lucrezia.
她还没回家吗?
Has she not returned home?
她之前在这里 但几天前就动身回佛罗伦萨了
She was here, but she left for Florence days ago.
不好意思 我们要进去看一下
You understand we'll need to look around.
她走的是波吉邦西那条路
Did she take the road to Poggibonsi
还是基安蒂那边?
or through Chianti?
当然是波吉邦西了 那条路安全些
Poggibonsi, of course. It's safer.
如果你有她的消息 请立即给佛罗伦萨发信通知我
If you hear from her, send word to me immediately in Florence.
当然
Of course.
看啊
Behold.
如果这就是你要找的
If it is treasure you seek,
这间屋子可远超过了你期望的
this chamber contains more that you should ever require.
即使达芬奇也感到惊奇了吗
It appears we awe even Da Vinci.
我只是震惊于...
I'm just astonished...
一个暴虐专横的人能窃取如此之多
at what tyranny can steal.
这些精致的工艺品都是鲜血换来的
Blood was the ransom paid for these artifacts.
来自一个威胁我命的人的伪善
Hypocrisy from a man who threatens my life.
来自一个试图杀我的人的声音
Voiced by one who attempted to take mine.
是谁写的这封匿名信...
Whose agent authored this denunciation...
害我差点被烧死的
to have me burned.
这是一个女人的笔迹
But this is in a woman's hand.
难道你相信我会雇佣女人办事?
Could you truly believe I would employ a daughter of Eve as an agent?
我要找一把钥匙
I seek a key.
打开"天穹"的第二把钥匙
The second needed to open the Vault of Heaven.
为了这把钥匙你甘愿冒死?
For this you would risk death?
别继续... 玩你的把戏了
Do not continue... with this ruse.
你想拖延时间
You aim only to delay me
直到你的护卫发现你的失踪
until your absence is noticed by your guards.
你从不停止思考
Your mind is restless.
探索着那些最难以理解的东西
Yearning for that which most cannot comprehend.
上帝可以使你解脱
God can end your longing.
因为 他将送你一份大礼
For He presents you the chance to explore
给你一个机会去解开这间屋子内所有的谜
all the mysteries of this chamber.
只要你答应代替莫克里红衣大主教
If you would only agree to replace Cardinal Mercuri.
你在引诱我做一个密室的守护者?
You would entice me to become keeper of the Secret Archives?
不 不 不是守护者
Not keeper. Oh, no, no, no.
是探索者
Its explorer.
跟我来 达芬奇
Come with me, Da Vinci.
跟我来...
Come with me...
然后你就不会说没动心了
and then tell me you're not intrigued.
阁下 那现在怎么办?
So, what now, Signor?
如果她没什么好隐瞒的 她就会选择波吉邦西这条路
If she has nothing to hide, she'll take the road through Poggibonsi.
但如果她背着我们策划什么
But if she conspires against us,
她就会选择一个人走基安蒂这条路
she'd find a way to ride alone through Chianti.
那我们走哪条路?
Which road do we take?
我们做最坏的打算 即使推测错误 也不会耽误什么
We prepare for the worst and find ourselves relieved if we were wrong.
走基安蒂
Through Chianti.
- 卡拉 他们是谁?  - 洛伦佐的弟弟
- Cara mia, who were they?  - That was Lorenzo's brother.
或许是我离开的太久了
Perhaps I've been away too long.
或许是你在罗马的事情败坏了
Or perhaps your own business in Rome has gone bad.
我希望你别管这些事
I'd hoped to spare you knowledge of these matters.
在佛罗伦萨就没有一个人肯帮你吗? 洛伦佐呢?
Can no-one in Florence help you? What about Lorenzo?
洛伦佐把一个忠心耿耿跟随他多年的人送上刑场
He sentenced a man he's loved for decades to death,
因为他怀疑那人背叛了他
on suspicion of something I have done.
那就没有别人了吗?
Well, is there no-one else?
有
Yes.
还有一个人
There is another.
有一个可以凭空找到出路的人
A man who could invent an escape where none exists.
龙的头骨
The skull of a dragon.
这会成为你研究生物
It would serve as a unique addition to your study
和解剖工作的良机 不是吗?
of creatures and their anatomy, yes?
或许你想要细看一下这个
Perhaps you'd care to examine this.
命运之矛
The Spear of Destiny.
在基督被挂在十字架上的时候
A lance used to pierce the side of Christ
它曾刺过他
while He hung on the cross.
很多人相信 此矛在手...
Many believe that in one's hands...
天下无敌
it can defeat any enemy.
巧夺天工
It's extraordinary.
但钥匙呢?
But what of the key?
关乎叶之书啊
This obsession with the Book Of Leaves.
那个土耳其人在玩弄你
The Turk blinds you with tricks and deceptions.
密特拉之子们早就灭绝了
The Sons of Mithras are an extinct order.
那些借他名义的人
Those who advance its name now,
都想把真正身份隐藏起来
conceal their real agenda.
从你的行踪看来 你在不知情的情况下为土耳其帝国的苏丹人做事
In your quest, you unknowingly act as an agent for the Ottoman Sultan.
我不听命于任何人...
My quest is not in pursuit of anyone's purpose...
除了我自己
except my own.
啊
Ah.
我猜现在 你代表你母亲说话
And here, you speak of your mother, I presume.
这确实是一件值得为之奋斗的事情
A treasure truly worth fighting for.
而且只有我能让你们重新团聚
And one only I can aid in reuniting you with.
你知道我的母亲?
What do you know of my mother?
圣父?
Holy Father?
圣父!
Holy Father!
有人潜入了梵蒂冈教廷
An enemy has entered the Vatican.
蒙泰费尔特罗 拉响警报
Montefeltro, sound the alarm.
效忠罗马
Pledge your allegiance to Rome
整个天主教教会的所有资源都将为你所用
and you shall have the entire resources of the Catholic Church at your disposal.
钱 物 人
Its coffers, devisings,
就是教廷舰队也会听你的派遣
even the ships of the Papal Armada to ferry you.
那叶之书呢? 如果我的研究需要用到这本书呢?
And the Book Of Leaves? What if I should uncover that on my search?
那就更好了
So much the better.
它太珍贵了 无人守护我可不放心
It's far too precious to be left unguarded.
有时候我都怀疑它是否存在
There was a time when I distrusted its very existence.
直到我亲眼看到它
Until my eyes fell upon this.
我们从佛罗伦萨获得来的战利品
Which we recovered from Florence.
噢!
Oh!
这不是任何一种我所知道的语言
It's unlike any language I've ever encountered.
远不止语言本身的魅力
That is far from its only mystery.
这些字...
The words...
它们好像... 每看一次都会改变?
they seem to... change with every viewing?
同样的内容 从没出现过第二次
Never offering the same content twice.
想象着解开这个谜
Imagine solving this.
我见到这个东西不久之后就做了一个梦
I had a dream not long after I saw this.
来自天堂的强烈的信息
A powerful message sent from the heavens.
告诉我叶之书
It told me the Book Of Leaves
里面有... 神的秘密
contains... secrets of the divine.
它的作者是"堕落者"
That its authors were the Nephilim
神和人所生之子
the offspring of Angels and the women of man.
圣父!
Father!
我知道那本书和它的秘密一定
I know now that the Book with its mysteries
藏在教会里
must remain within the Church.
- 无论代价如何  - 你打算用它来守护自己还是埋葬自己?
- No matter the cost.  - Is it defense or burial that you intend as its fate?
世界需要秘密
The world needs secrets.
如果天机泄漏 将会天翻地覆
Powerful ideas can wreak havoc if unleashed before their time.
但同时也是一个崭新的开始 这将取决于你
But a new beginning can start with you here now, if you choose.
住手 蒙泰费尔特罗
Hold, Montefeltro.
那么... 我们是同盟了
So... we are allied.
你强迫我为你做事
You press for my devotion
囚禁我的自由
as only to place me here
如同你亲手打造的坟墓里的一件陪葬品
as another relic in this tomb that you've constructed.
抓起来
Take him.
抓住他!
Get him!
走!
Go!
尼科! 回来 憨货
Nico! Come back here, you spongy pignut.
你的主人回来了
Your master returns.
尼科!
Nico!
莱昂
Leo.
过来
Come here.
你肯定是疯了
You are completely mad.
该死
Oh, fuck.
真难相信你耍了那个瑞阿里奥
I can't believe you stuck it to that fuck Riario.
我真想看看他知道真相之后的样子
I wish I could see his face when he figures it out.
梦想成真了
Wishes come true.
在这边
Through here.
达芬奇去哪了?
Where is Da Vinci?
只有我知道
I'm the last person he tells.
- 是吗?  - 是
- Really?  - Yeah.
那么... 也许我等他的时候
Then... then perhaps I'll entertain myself,
可以自娱自乐一下
while I wait.
梵蒂冈教廷可以增加一个阉割过的歌手
The Vatican choir could use a new castrato.
该死
Fuck.
闪开
Move away.
哈!
Yeaargh!
啊!
Aaargh!
哦
Oh.
啊!
Aaargh!
天啊! 该死! 啊
God! Fuck! Aargh.
你知道我是谁吗?
Do you know who I am?
小尼科
Young Nico.
我... 我发现咱们第一次相遇让你的手还一直颤抖
I... I see our first encounter left your hand shaking.
我会刺进你心里
I'll steady it in your heart.
你会吗? 如果你想报仇
Will you? If revenge is your aim,
必须战胜自己的恐惧
you must overcome your apprehension.
好的 我也表达了自己的直率
Now that we've established my propensity for directness,
我要问你个问题
I have a question for you.
我的大师在哪?
Where is my Maestro?
你尝过血的味道吗 尼科?
Have you ever tasted blood, Nico?
嗯... 有一种奇怪的咸味
It erm... possesses a peculiar saltiness.
别麻烦了 尼科 他不知道
Don't bother, Nico. He doesn't know.
他就算知道也会装不知道
Wouldn't reveal anything even if he did.
- 对 是的  - 很对 尼科
- Yes, he will.  - You're quite right, Nico.
我可以给你讲讲在我们讲话的时候
I will tell you all about the dozen Swiss mercenaries,
我往台伯河边派出的
I dispatched to the Tiber,
一沓搜寻我的瑞士雇佣军
who search for me as we speak.
等他们来了我给你讲讲我的计划
I'll reveal my plan when they arrive,
让他们一层层地把你的皮剥下来
to have them peel away your skin one layer at a time.
就这样?
Like this?
啊!
Aaargh!
你不会想这样的
You don't want to travel this road.
如果你想让他流血 让我动手 行了 可以了
If you wish to see him bleed, let it be my doing. Come on, stop it.
不！我要对抗他 他要回答我的问题
No! He's mine to face. And he will answer my question.
他在哪?
Where is he?
我很欣赏你的决心 孩子
I commend you on your resolve, boy.
换做别人 若非此景此景
In another life, in other circumstances,
我一定跟你一样
I could have used someone like you.
啊!
Aaaarh!
是第二把钥匙
It's the second key.
啊!
Aargh!
好吧...
Okay...
这个曲调很熟悉
That's a curious tune.
我能问问... 你从哪学的吗?
May I ask... where you know it from?
是我编的曲子
It's of my own construction.
我听过这支摇篮曲
I've heard the lullaby before.
你是卢克蕾齐娅・多纳蒂的父亲
You are Lucrezia Donati's father.
对吧?
Aren't you?
是的... 达芬奇阁下
Indeed... Signor Da Vinci.
我们以前见过吗?
Have we met before?
没有 不过还能有谁让瑞阿里奥如此苦恼呢?
No, but who else so bedevils Riario?
这只戒指是你的 对吧?
This ring belongs to you, doesn't it?
曾经是 被拿走了
Once upon a time. It was taken.
我能问问你是如何得到的吗?
May I ask how you acquired it?
是你女儿... 送给我的礼物
It was a gift... from your daughter.
不 这可不仅仅是礼物
No, it is far more than a gift.
你爱我女儿吗?
Do you love my daughter?
莱昂纳多 你爱卢克蕾齐娅吗?
Do you love my Lucrezia, Leonardo?
呵
Ha.
我必须承认...
I must confess...
我不确定你女儿是谁 阁下
I'm not sure who your daughter is, Signor.
她的身影... 对我来说如此飘渺
Her image has always been... shaded to me.
也许现在我知道了原因
Perhaps now I know why.
你...
You...
你就是...
You present...
解开她谜题的关键因素
a key piece in unlocking her puzzle.
她送给我你的戒指
She offers me your ring,
却留你在监狱里...
but keeps your imprison...
她对你被监禁的事只字不提
She keeps your imprisonment a secret.
她...
She...
给了我她的爱...
extends me her love...
却仍然与洛伦佐纠缠
but she continues with Lorenzo.
她几乎没见过瑞阿里奥... 却如此鄙视
She despises Riario... but she's barely met him.
她想... 救你
She hopes... to save you.
保护...
To protect...
这是女人的笔迹
This is in a woman's hand.
你为什么会如此盲目?
How can you be so blind?
她是受罗马操纵的
She maneuvers for Rome.
她把我的秘密告知了瑞阿里奥
She feeds my secrets to Riario.
她... 她毒害自己同城的人民
She... she poisons her fellow citizens.
她看着我入狱 等待火刑
She sees me imprisoned and left to burn.
一切都是为了救你
And it's all to set you free.
卢克蕾齐娅全都是按照别人残酷的操纵行动的
Lucrezia acts at the behest of others' cruel manipulations.
她爱我 请将此归罪于我
She loves me. Blame that on me if you will.
而不是她
Not her.
用力!
Harder!
请从暗影中现身
Remove yourself from the shadows.
我们共同面对你的女儿
Let us face your daughter together.
卢克蕾齐娅努力要拯救你为什么还不走?
Lucrezia labors to secure your freedom why stay?
我就在自己应该在的地方
I'm exactly where I need to be.
我不明白
I don't understand.
走吧 莱昂纳多
Go now, Leonardo.
回到我女儿身边
Return to my daughter.
向她表达我的爱
Tell her of my love.
还有你自己的
And your own.
别着急 尼科 他没事
Don't brood, Nico. He's fine.
你刚才
What you did earlier,
帮助我的行为 非常勇敢
coming to my aid, was very brave.
呃... 谢谢
So... thank you.
那我也该谢你
Then I should thank you as well.
大师! 我们很担心你
Maestro! You had us worried.
至少尼科很担心
Nico, at least.
我只是很高兴能离开这里了
I'm just glad to leave this hellhole.
恐怕... 恐怕...
I'm afraid... I'm afraid...
还不行
I'm afraid I can't.
我没拿到钥匙所以还不能走
I've failed to retrieve the key and I'll stay until I acquire it.
- 莱昂  - 怎么?
- Leo.  - What?
有个惊喜给你 别太高兴
Steel yourself for a surprise.
什么?
How?
因为他这个酒鬼
Credit this malt-worm.
我本来想把这个家伙刺死 可是他不让
I wanted to gut the prick, but he'd not have it.
呵
Huh.
艺术家... 我看到你逃出来了
Artista... I see you escaped.
而我看到了一把钥匙...
And I see a key...
是你要给我的
that you will be giving to me.
你最好先杀了我
You best kill me first.
不然就算追到天涯海角 我也要找回属于我自己的东西
I will follow you to the ends of the earth to retrieve what's mine.
或许有一天...
There may come a day...
我会不得已而取你性命 捷洛拉莫
where I am forced to take your life, Girolamo.
可不是今天
It's not today.
我来到了你的家园...
I've come into your home...
拿走了你最珍爱的东西
and I've taken the thing that you hold dearest.
我...
I erm...
会很快报答你的...
I plan to return the favor soon...
夺走你最珍爱的人
and take the one most dearest to you.
大师 我们就把他留在这?
Maestro, shall we just leave him?
被自己过错阴魂不散得萦绕 尼科...
To be haunted by your mistakes, Nico...
是比死亡更悲惨的命运
that's a fate far worse than death.
别碰她 她不干净
Don't touch her. She's unclean.
难道没人告诉我们她会伪装吗?
Weren't we told she'd be in disguise?
我们不能让她过去 去拦住她
We can't pass her by. We're stopping her.
停!
Halt!
停下 停!
Halt. Halt!
停下!
Halt!
别动
Stay where you are.
依慕达!
Immunda!
- 露出脸来!  - 我很可怕
- Unveil yourself!  - I'm hideous.
是个女人 瑞阿里奥说过她会伪装成麻风病人
It's a woman. Riario said she'd be disguised as a leper.
自己露出脸来不然我们就动手了
Show your face or we do it for you.
摘掉面具
Take off the mask.
看看她一个手指都没掉
Look who has all her fingers.
不!
No!
你不是麻风病人 女士
You're no leper, Signora.
退下! 我奉罗马瑞阿里奥伯爵之命
Stand down! I've been given orders by Count Riario of Rome,
为洛伦佐・美第奇传信
to bring information for Lorenzo de Medici.
女士 看来你的消息有点过时了
Signora, you seem to be a sunrise behind.
我们也是奉罗马的命令
We're on our own orders from Rome.
洛伦佐和他的弟弟将会被刺杀
Lorenzo and his dolt of a brother are to be assassinated.
你的任务结束了 生命也是
Your services are ended. As is your life.
我还没杀过这么漂亮的人
I've never killed anyone quite so pretty.
这次可不一样了
This will be different.
他说了要做的像强盗杀人越货的现场 不要一剑封喉
He said to make it look like brigands. Don't do one clean hit.
不
No.
对抗我们
That's for fighting us.
不!
No!
不过首先 咱们让她爽爽
But first, let's give her something to remember.
住手! 退下!
Halt! Stand down!
不关你的事 走开
This doesn't concern you. Ride on.
我是朱利亚诺・美第奇
I am Giuliano de Medici,
佛罗伦萨总督洛伦佐阁下的弟弟
brother to His Magnificence, Lorenzo of Florence.
我命令你们停手!
I order you to stop!
罗马在这里没有权利
Romans have no authority here.
很快就会有了
They will soon enough.
而且罗马要这个不可靠的小婊子死
And they want this deceptive little tart dead.
她怎样冒犯了罗马?
How has she offended Rome?
她是瑞阿里奥伯爵的间谍 不过现在已经弃用了
She spied for Count Riario and now he's done with her.
帕吉家族想要掌控佛罗伦萨 用得着这样一个荡妇吗?
What use is a slattern like this with the Pazzis about to seize control of Florence?
啊!
Aaargh!
阁下!
Signor!
啊!
Aaargh!
博尔蒂诺!
Bertino!
啊!
Aaargh!
都是拜你这个间谍所赐!
All this for a spy like you!
博尔蒂诺是个好人 贝奇也是
Bertino was a good man. But so was Becchi.
你根本不知道好有何意义
Goodness means nothing to you.
是你给他带去了毒芹 对吧?
The hand that brought him the hemlock was yours, wasn't it?
是什么让你背叛洛伦佐?
What possesses you to betray Lorenzo?
背叛我们大家?
To betray us all?
你永远不会明白
You would never understand.
啊!
Aaargh!
你这个欲壑难填的浪货
You are the cunt of an overworked whore.
我哥哥操你的时候
As my brother fucked you in the ass,
你是不是因为知道也在毁掉他 所以才能笑得出来?
did you smile, knowing you were doing the same to him?
我要带你回去见他 看他会有何感觉
Let's return to him and see how he feels about all this.
他会以祸乱民众
Will he opt to break you on the wheel,
把你绑在广场的木轮上 被乱棍打死吗?
in the public square, for the edification of the masses?
还是会因羞愧而私下处你死刑?
Or will his shame lead him to kill you privately?
慢慢地 经历数周
Slowly, over weeks of time.
- 呃!  - 啊!
- Urgh!  - Oh!
啊! 啊!
Aargh! Aargh!
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: Leon
翻译：SceneryJuly 爱哈利波特 落寞卷菜 sharefans_竺
校对：sharefans_竺 影子